Guide to the NewMusicBox Interviews
NewMusicBox Interviews
Oral History of American Music
NewMusicBox Interviews
1999 2013
NMB
Oral History of American Music
148 Videocassettes (MiniDV)
167 Computer Files
291.8 gigabytes
1 External Hard Drive
4.29 terabytes
Oteri, Frank J., 1964-
New Music USA
Content Description
108 interviews as of September 2, 2021. Interviews conducted for NewMusicBox, the online magazine for New Music USA.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, these interviews may have been transcribed. Please see contact OHAM for more details.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Appraisal
When processing the computer files in this collection, a number of non-essenital system generated files were removed, leaving just the audio and video files.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The computer files in this collection incorporate video (.mov and .mp4) and audio content (.ogg and .wav). Streaming versions of each digital video file have been provided for access.
Music United States 21st century; Composers United States 21st century; Born digital; Computer files
- Adams, John
  - Adams, John, 2000 November 11; 4 Computer Files; 3.44 gigabytes
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Includes both audio (.ogg) and video (.mp4) copies of the interview.
    Conditions Governing Access
    As a preservation measure, original computer files may not be used. Digital access copies must be provided for use.
    Adams, John, 1947-
- Adams, John Luther
  - Adams, John Luther, 2011 February 18; 29 Computer Files; 32.3 gigabytes
    Includes both audio (.wav) and video (.mov) copies of the interview.
    Adams, John Luther, 1953-
- Adamo, Mark
  - Adamo, Mark, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952574)
    Adamo, Mark (1962)
- Alsop, Marin
  - Alsop, Marin, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952632)
    Alsop, Marin (1956-10-16-)
- Ashley, Robert
  - Ashley, Robert, 2001 March 13; 4 Computer Files; 3.20 gigabytes
    Ashley, Robert, 1930-2014
- Babbitt, Milton
  - Babbitt, Milton, 2001 October 16; 1 Computer File; 1.97 gigabytes
    Video (.mp4) file.
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011
- Bang on a Can
  - Bang on a Can (Part 1), 1999 March 24; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952004)
    Bang on a Can; Lang, David (David A.) (1957-01-08-); Gordon, Michael, 1956-; Wolfe, Julia (19581218)
  - Bang on a Can (Part 2), 1999 March 24; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952012)
  - Bang on a Can (Part 3), 1999 March 24; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952020)
- Brant, Henry
  - Brant, Henry, 2002 October 4; 4 Computer Files; 4.21 gigabytes
    Brant, Henry, 1913-2008
- Bley, Carla
  - Bley, Carla, 2003 June 10; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952103)
    Bley, Carla
- Brick, Andy
  - Brick, Andy, 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952285)
    Brick, Andy
- Broido, Arnold and Tom
  - Broido, Arnold and Tom, 2000 January 7; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951956)
    Broido, Arnold; Broido, Tom
- Brooke, Nick
  - Brooke, Nick, 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952277)
    Brooke, Nicholas (Nicholas James)
- Byron, Don
  - Byron, Don, 1999 December 18; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952483)
    Byron, Don (1958-12-08-)
- Carter, Elliott
  - Carter, Elliott, 2000 February 4; 1 Computer File; 1.39 gigabytes
    Carter, Elliott, 1908-2012
- Chen Yi
  - Chen Yi, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952475)
    This material is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
    Chen, Yi, 1953-
- Chen Yi and Zhou Long
  - Chen Yi and Zhou Long, 2006; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952590)
    Zhou, Long, 1953-; Chen, Yi, 1953-
- Chou Wen-Chung
  - Chou, Wen-Chung, 2013 January 16; 29 Computer Files; 34.9 gigabytes
    Chou, Wen-Chung, 1923-2019
- Collins, Nicolas
  - Collins, Nicolas (Part 1), 2006; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952392)
    Collins, Nicolas
  - Collins, Nicolas (Part 2), 2006; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952400)
- Cone, Edward T.
  - Cone, Edward T., undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952723)
    Cone, Edward T., 1917-2004
- Corigliano, John
  - Corigliano, John, 2004 December 9; 2 Computer Files; 22.1 gigabytes
    Video (.mov) files.
    Corigliano, John, 1938-
- Crumb, George
  - Crumb, George, 2002 July 12; 1 Computer File; 3.99 gigabytes
    Video (.mov) file.
    Crumb, George, 1929-
- Cunningham, Merce
  - Cunningham, Merce (Part 1), 2002 April 17; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952178)
    Cunningham, Merce (19190416-20090726)
  - Cunningham, Merce (Part 2), 2002 April 17; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952186)
- Curran, Alvin
  - Curran, Alvin, 2003 November 26; 4 Computer Files; 4.02 gigabytes
    Curran, Alvin S., 1938-
- Daugherty, Michael
  - Daugherty, Michael, 2006 December 9 2006 December 11; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952640)
    Daugherty, Michael, 1954-
- Del Tredici, David
  - Del Tredici, David, 2003; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952111)
    Del Tredici, David
- Dessner, Bryce
  - Dessner, Bryce, 2019 November 13; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 316 Computer Files; 133 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 66 mins
    Interview Location
    New York, NY
    .jpg, .mov, .mp3, .wav files
    Dessner, Bryce (1976-04-23-)
- Duffy, John
  - Duffy, John (Part 1), 2003 October 22; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952079)
    Duffy, John, 1926-2015
  - Duffy, John (Part 2), 2003 October 22; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952087)
- Eaton, John
  - Eaton, John (Part 1), 2000 August 3; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952681)
    Eaton, John, 1935-2015
  - Eaton, John (Part 2), 2000 August 3; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952699)
- Einhorn, Richard
  - Einhorn, Richard, 2001 August 10; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952046)
    Einhorn, Richard, 1952 August 2-
- Ferneyhough, Brian
  - Ferneyhough, Brian, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952426)
    Ferneyhough, Brian, 1943-
  - Ferneyhough, Brian, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952467)
- Frank, Gabriela Lena
  - Frank, Gabriela Lena, 2008 February 5; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 2 Videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002038325230, Item barcode 39002038325222)
    Interview location
    Frank, Gabriela Lena (1972)
- Galás, Diamánda
  - Galás, Diamánda, 2003 August 4; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952095)
    Galás, Diamánda
- Glass, Philip
  - Glass, Philip, 2001 October 9; 1 Computer File; 953 megabytes
    Glass, Philip
- Goldenthal, Elliot
  - Goldenthal, Elliot, 2003 September 1; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951907)
    Goldenthal, Elliot (19540502)
- Gosfield, Annie
  - Gosfield, Annie, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952236)
    Gosfield, Annie, 1960-
- Harbison, John
  - Harbison, John, 2011 October 3; 10 Computer Files; 17.8 gigabytes
    Harbison, John, 1938-
- Higdon, Jennifer
  - Higdon, Jennifer, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952608)
    Higdon, Jennifer, 1962-
- Hitchcock, H. Wiley
  - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 2002 November 13; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952442)
    Hitchcock, H. Wiley (Hugh Wiley), 1923-2007
- Ho, Fred
  - Ho, Fred, 2008 October 8; 2 Computer Files; 20.6 gigabytes
    Ho, Fred Wei-han (19570810-20140412)
- Jazz Composers Collective
  - Jazz Composers Collective, 2001 February 8; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952038)
    Scope and Contents
    Allison, Ben; Blake, Michael; Horton, Ron; Kimbrough, Frank; Nash, Ted.
    Allison, Ben (19661117); Blake, Michael, 1964-; Horton, Ron (19600212); Kimbrough, Frank (19561102); Nash, Ted, 1959-
- Jeanrenaud, Joan
  - Jeanrenaud, Joan, 2000 September 11; Jeanrenaud, Joan (19560125); 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952053)
- Jenkins, Leroy
  - Jenkins, Leroy, 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952293)
    Jenkins, Leroy (19320311-20070224)
- Jones, Bill T. and Daniel Bernard Roumain (DBR)
  - Jones, Bill T. and Daniel Bernard Roumain (DBR), 2006; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952418)
    Jones, Bill T.; Roumain, Daniel Bernard (1971)
- Jordan, Sheila
  - Jordan, Sheila, 2015 April 6; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 94 Computer Files; 57 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 80 mins
    .jpg, .mov, .mp3, .mp4, .wav files
    Jordan, Sheila, 1928-
- Kander, John
  - Kander, John, 2010 April 7; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002038325206)
    Kander, John
- Krakauer, David
  - Krakauer, David, 2004 December 2; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952343)
    Krakauer, David, 1956-
- La Barbara, Joan
  - La Barbara, Joan, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952210)
    La Barbara, Joan, 1947-
  - La Barbara, Joan, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952228)
- Lanier, Jaron
  - Lanier, Jaron (Part 1), 2002 June 5; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952376)
    Lanier, Jaron (19600503)
  - Lanier, Jaron (Part 2), 2002 June 5; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952384)
- Lansky, Paul and George Perle
  - Lansky, Paul and George Perle, 2002 February 19; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952145)
    Lansky, Paul, 1944-; Perle, George, 1915-2009
- Lansky, Paul and Virgil Moorefield
  - Lansky, Paul and Virgil Moorefield, 2002 April 5; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952152)
    Lansky, Paul, 1944-; Moorefield, Virgil, 1956-
- León, Tania
  - León, Tania (Part 1), 1999 July 12; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951972)
    León, Tania (1943-05-14-)
  - León, Tania (Part 2), 1999 July 12; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951980)
- Lewis, George
  - Lewis, George, 2010 May 11; 2 Computer Files; 24.5 gigabytes
    Lewis, George, 1952-
- Lockwood, Annea
  - Lockwood, Annea, 2003 November 11; 2 Computer Files; 15.4 gigabytes
    Lockwood, Annea, 1939-
- Lucas, Gary
  - Lucas, Gary (Part 1), 2000 June 22; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951915)
    Lucas, Gary (1952-06-20-)
  - Lucas, Gary (Part 2), 2000 June 22; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951923)
- Lucier, Alvin
  - Lucier, Alvin, 2005 February 9; 1 Computer File; 14 gigabytes
    Lucier, Alvin, 1931-
- Machover, Tod
  - Machover, Tod, 1999 August 18; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951998)
    Machover, Tod (1953)
- Mackey, Steve
  - Mackey, Steve, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952616)
    Mackey, Steven, 1956-
- Marshall, Ingram
  - Marshall, Ingram, 2001 July 17; 2 Computer Files; 586 megabytes
    Marshall, Ingram, 1942-
- Mesinai, Raz (Badawi)
  - Mesinai, Raz (Badawi), 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952251)
    Badawi, 1973-
  - Mesinai, Raz (Badawi), 2005 September 21; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952269)
- Monk, Meredith
  - Monk, Meredith, 2000 March 16; 1 Computer File; 13 gigabytes
    Monk, Meredith (1942-11-20-)
- Muhly, Nico
  - Muhly, Nico, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952194)
    Muhly, Nico (19810826)
  - Muhly, Nico, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952202)
- Oliveros, Pauline
  - Oliveros, Pauline, 2000 November 8; 1 Computer File; 16.1 gigabytes
    Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-2016
- Picker, Tobias
  - Picker, Tobias, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952657)
    Picker, Tobias, 1954-
- Rakowski, David
  - Rakowski, David, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952491)
    Rakowski, David (1958)
- Reed, Foster
  - Reed, Foster, 1999 May 10; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951964)
    Reed, Foster
- Riley, Terry
  - Riley, Terry, 2001 February 16; 1 Computer File; 859 megabytes
    Riley, Terry, 1935-
- Rorem, Ned
  - Rorem, Ned, 2006 March 13; 2 Computer Files; 6 gigabytes
    Video (.mp4) files.
    Rorem, Ned, 1923-
- Rosenfeld, Marina and Stephen Vitiello
  - Rosenfeld, Marina and Stephen Vitiello (Part 1), 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952327)
    Rosenfeld, Marina (1968-); Vitiello, Stephen (1964-)
  - Rosenfeld, Marina and Stephen Vitiello (Part 2), 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952335)
- Rzewski, Frederic
  - Rzewski, Frederic, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952707)
    Rzewksi, Frederic
- Salonen, Esa-Pekka
  - Salonen, Esa-Pekka, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952715)
    Salonen, Esa-Pekka, 1958-
- Schick, Steven
  - Schick, Steven, 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952319)
    Schick, Steven (1954-)
- Schickele, Peter
  - Schickele, Peter, 2004; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952301)
    Schickele, Peter (1935-07-17-)
- Schneider, Maria
  - Schneider, Maria, 2008 October 1; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002038325172)
    Schneider, Maria, 1960-
- Scott, Stephen
  - Scott, Stephen, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952459)
    Scott, Stephen, 1944-
- Sharp, Elliott
  - Sharp, Elliott, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952244)
    Sharp, Elliott (19510301)
- Shaw, Caroline
  - Shaw, Caroline, 2015 February 19; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 173 Computer Files; 27 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 90 mins
    .jpg, .mp4, .mov, .prproj fiiles
    Shaw, Caroline (Caroline Adelaide) (1982-)
- Shipp, Matthew
  - Shipp, Matthew, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952525)
    Shipp, Matthew (1960-12-07-)
  - Shipp, Matthew, 2005; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952533)
    Outside container label indicates this is "Part 2" of an interview.
- Sinha, Natasha
  - Sinha, Natasha (Part 1), 2001 May 24; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952350)
    Sinha, Natasha, 1990-
  - Sinha, Natasha (Part 2), 2001 May 24; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952368)
- Slatkin, Leonard
  - Slatkin, Leonard, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952061)
    Slatkin, Leonard (19440901)
- Smith, Wadada Leo
  - Smith, Wadada Leo, 2011 December 14; 22 Computer Files; 20.2 gigabytes
    Smith, Wadada Leo, 1941-
- Sorey, Tyshawn
  - Sorey, Tyshawn, 2019 September 11; 23 Computer Files; 34 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 62 mins
    Middletown, CT
    .jpg. .mov, .wav files
    Sorey, Tyshawn, 1980-
- Spratlan, Lewis
  - Spratlan, Lewis (Part 1), 2000 April 21; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951931)
    Spratlan, Lewis (1940)
  - Spratlan, Lewis (Part 2), 2000 April 21; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132951949)
- Stone, Carl
  - Stone, Carl, 2000 October 17; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952160)
    Stone, Carl, 1953-
- Tan, Dun
  - Tan, Dun, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952434)
    Tan, Dun, 1957-
- Tate, Jerod Impichcha̲achaaha̕
  - Tate, Jerod Impichcha̲achaaha̕, 2011 2012; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952509)
    Tate, Jerod Impichcha̲achaaha̕, 1968-
  - Tate, Jerod Impichcha̲achaaha̕, undated; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002038325164)
- Tenney, James
  - Tenney, James, 2005 May 8; 2 Computer Files; 2.18 gigabytes
    Date note
    Date based on the one provided on NewMusicBox website.
    Tenney, James, 1934-2006
  - Tenney, James, 2005 May 11; 2 Computer Files; 1.91 gigabytes
- Threadgill, Henry
  - Threadgill, Henry, 2010 August 26; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 2 Videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002038325180, Item barcode 39002038325198)
    Threadgill, Henry (19440215)
- Tilson Thomas, Michael
  - Tilson Thomas, Michael, 2001 April 16; Oteri, Frank J., 1964-; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 2, Item barcode 39002038328150, Item barcode 39002038328168)
    Miami Beach, FL
    Tilson Thomas, Michael, 1944-
- Tower, Joan
  - Tower, Joan, 2005 September 15; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952517)
    Tower, Joan, 1938-
  - Tower, Joan, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952624)
- Upshaw, Dawn
  - Upshaw, Dawn, 2002 January 3; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952129)
    Upshaw, Dawn (19600717)
- Weiss, Tim
  - Weiss, Tim, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 2, Item barcode 39002038328192)
    Oberlin College in Oberlin, OH
    Weiss, Timothy
- Wolff, Christian
  - Wolff, Christian, 2002 January 11; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952137)
    Wolff, Christian, 1934-
- Wuorinen, Charles
  - Wuorinen, Charles, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952541)
    Pre concert talk
    Wuorinen, Charles, 1938-
  - Wuorinen, Charles, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952558)
    Dante Trilogy. Miller Theatre.
  - Wuorinen, Charles, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952566)
    Tape 3.
- Zhou, Long
  - Zhou, Long, undated; 1 Videocassette (MiniDV) (Box 1, Item barcode 39002132952582)
    Zhou, Long, 1953-
- Zwilich, Ellen Taaffe
  - Zwilich, Ellen Taaffe, 2011 April 29; 37 Computer Files; 26.2 gigabytes
    Zwilich, Ellen Taaffe, 1939-